Guide to the William Somerset Maugham collection, 1921-1979 (inclusive), 1921-1958 (bulk) M0013
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Alan Searle to Alanson, 1955-1958; 26 letters (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 23. Cap Ferrat AS to BA, 1958 January 28; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Willie's birthday, Winston.
  - 24. Venice AS to BA, 1958 April 25; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Death of Alanson's brother, sketch on envelope.
  - 25. Vevey AS to BA, 1958 May 18; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Willie's medical check-up, “Stanford to get the manuscript of the Ten Novelists' and I shall let them have my collection of Maughamiana. All the first editions, a lot of letters addressed to Willie by eminent people, photographs, “etc.”.
  - 26. Cap Ferrat, 1957 [?]; Tel 1p. + envelope
    Willie much better.
- Robin Maugham to Alanson, 1937-1958; 21 letters (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1. London Robin Maugham to BA, 1937 August 19; ALS 5pp. (5) + envelope
    To stay with Alansons.
  - 2. Grenoble RM to BA, [1937 September 27]; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Trip to the U.S. by ship, to stay in Hollywood a few days.
  - 3. Washington, D.C. RM to BA, 1938 March 4; APCS 1p. (1)
    Staying with Michael Straight, Dr. Genthe.
  - 4. Bedford RM to BA, 1939 January 17; ALS 6pp. (6) + envelope
    Thank you letter for a tie, working as a judge's marshall, Bar exams, reaction to Germany's treatment of Jews.
  - 5. London [RM] to BA, 1939 October 18; AL 8pp. (8)
    Prime Minister's return from Munich, hysteria in England, approaching war, Willie has put on weight, England in winter.
  - 6. [Middle East] RM to BA, 1942 April 6; ALS 1p. (1) + envelope
    In tank battles, desert.
  - 7. London RM to BA, 1943 November 23; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Editing a paper “which I hope will do something to help the War Effort, Xmas and “happier” New Year which will see the final defeat of the Japanese and the Germans. Envelope bears Censor's label.
  - 8. London RM to BA, 1948; ALS 2pp. (2)
    To take a holiday.
  - 9. London RM to BA, 1949 December 11; ALS 3pp. (3)
    Grateful to Willie, learning about business.
  - 10. London RM to BA, 1953 October 23; TLS 1p. (1)
    His film The Intruder opened in Edinburgh to good reviews.
  - 11. London RM to BA, 1954 June 17; TLS 2pp. (2)
    “Daddy” at 87 finished his book, family. WSM awarded Companion of Honour, RM has finished a novel.
  - 12. London RM to BA, 1954 December 1; TLS 1p. (1)
    Writing a film script from The Rough and the Smooth.
  - 13. London RM to BA, 1955 March 3; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Health, family, new novel.
  - 14. London RM to BA, 1955 September 30; TLS 1p. (1)
    Film: The Black Tent being made in Tripoli.
  - 15. London RM to BA, 1955 October 27; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Willie and father, publication of RM's book, Honor Earl (RM's sister) commissioned to do portraits in NY.
  - 16. London RM to BA, 1956 February 24; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Knee operation, new play sold to Herbert Shumlin.
  - 17. Sussex RM to BA, [1956 June 21]; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Film The Black Tent, family, financial matters.
  - 18. Hove RM to BA, 1957 June 21; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Sends reviews of one play, another opening, congratulations from Willie.
  - 19. Hove RM to BA, 1957 August 30; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Play reviews, his month in San Francisco with the Alansons.
  - 20. London RM to BA, 1958 April 8; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Death of his father.
  - 21. Hove RM to BA, 1958 December 4; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Willie pleased with R's new play, other productions of his work.
- Arthur Wilson to Alanson, 1954-1956; 12 letters (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1. Zurich AW to BA, 1954 March 9; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Terrible weather in Europe.
  - 2. Oreville AW to Gen. Howard M. Snyder, Denver, 1955; TL 2pp.
    President's heart attack, Thomas Mattingly, medical advice, regards to Mrs. Eisenhower.
  - 3. Frankfurt/Main AW to BA, 1956 January 29; TMsS 3pp. (3) with Ms corrections
    President's health and politics.
  - 4. Frankfurt/Main AW to BA, 1956 February 1; TLS 1p. (1) with ANS
    Ellen, stocks, Coca Cola report, health.
  - 5. Frankfurt/Main AW to BA, 1956 February 14; TLS 1p. (1) with ANS by Ellen + envelope.
    Health, stocks, Eisenhower.
  - 6. Bonn AW to BA, [1956] February 24; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Visiting, Ike will run again.
  - 7. Stuttgart AW to BA, 1956 March 1; Tel 1p. (1)
    “Congratulations letters received...”
  - 8. Zurich AW to BA, 1956 March 7; Tel 1p. (1) with [postal receipt?] + envelope APCS 1p. (1)
    Stocks, Stevenson and Ike, conferences.
  - 9. NY AW to BA Very cold weather in Europe., 1956 November 2
  - 10. AW to BA, 1956 March 6; APCS 1p. (1)
    APO Travel plans.
  - 11. APO AW to BA, 1956 February 13; envelope only (1)
  - 12. APO AW to BA, 1956 [?]; envelope only (1)
- Ellen Wilson to Alanson, 1956-1957; 14 letters (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1. Frankfurt/Main EW to BA, 1956 January 29; TLS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Congratulations on new Chrysler, Art's health.
  - 2. Bad Nornburg EW to BA, 1956 February 16; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Cold weather, transportation problems.
  - 3. Munich A and EW to BA, 1956 March 8; ALS 3pp. (3) + envelope and clipping
    BA and WSM, death of friends.
  - 4. APO EW to BA, 1956 March 12; APCS 1p.
    Mountains, family.
  - 5. Frankfurt/Main EW to BA, 1956 March 21; ALS 3pp. (3) + envelope
    Moving, health, coming home, Spring.
  - 6. APO New York A and EW to BA, [1956 March 28]; APCS 3pp. (3) + envelope
    Easter card with ANS 3pp. (3) of E and AW + envelope.
  - 7. Denver A and EW to BA, 1956 April 20; APCS 1p. (1) + envelope
    On the way home.
  - 8. Frankfurt/Main AW to BA, 1956 March 2; Envelope only (2)
  - 9. Oroville EW to BA, [1956 June 4]; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Trip postponed.
  - 10. [Oroville] EW to BA, 1956 October 29; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Death of AW.
  - 11. Oroville EW to BA, 1956 October 29; APCS 2pp. (2)
    with attached clipping about Maugham.
  - 12. Oroville EW to BA, [1957 May 17]; ANS 3pp. (2) + envelope
    To be in San Francisco 5/27 & 28.
  - 13. np EW to BA, [1957 October]; ANS 2pp. (2)
    Returned from Modesto, enclosure mentioned but not present.
  - 14. Cap Ferrat [AW?] to BA, 1956; Envelope only (1)
- Incoming Adams - Garcia - Gordon Loygorri (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1. Typed list of correspondents, 1p. (1).
  - 2. White House, Washington, D.C. Sherman Adams to BA, 1956 October 10; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Thanks for letter to President re: Mrs. Ellen Wilson's eligibility for naturalization.
  - 3. White House, Washington, D.C. Sherman Adams to BA, 1956 November 5; TLS 1p. (1)
    Mrs. Wilson's eligibility for naturalization.
  - 4. [Washington, D.C.] Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization to the Attorney General, Washington, D.C., [1956 October]; Carbon memo 1p. (1) + envelope
    Ellen Wilson.
  - 5. Stockton Warren H. Atherton to BA, 1957 June 21; TLS 2pp. (2)
    Political campaign.
  - 6. New York Harry Benjamin to BA, 1947 November 4; ALS 1p. (1)
    Picture of Arnold in action.
  - 7. New York H. Benjamin to BA, 1957; ANS on ptd appointment card.
  - 8. New York Douglas M. Black to BA (“Alanson”), 1952 October 28; TLS 1p. (1)
    Portrait arrived and is being forwarded.
  - 9. New York Douglas Black to BA, 1952 July 3
    WSM's dedication of the two new wings of Heineman's Wind-mill Press.
  - 10. New York DB to BA, 1956 October 25; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Death of Black's father, note from the President, and Doubleday's new plant in Virginia.
  - 11. New York DB to BA, 1957 October 23; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Alanson's new San Francisco Bay book, visitors from Europe, White House reception for the Queen, sends clipping about Maugham.
  - 12. Washington, D. C. Ned [Bruce] to BA, 1938 February 11; TLS 1p.
    Will miss seeing Maugham.
  - 13. np Maria Burger to BA, nd; Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 14. np Herb Caen to BA, nd; ANS 1p. (1)
    “Thanks so much for risking this with me...”.
  - 15. Berkeley, California Kenneth J. Carpenter to BA, 1956 April 19; TLS 1p. (1)
    Interested in Alanson's Maugham collection.
  - 16. Stockton Tom Connolly, Jr. to BA, [1956?]; TLS 1p. (2) with ANS of “Marietta”.
    Seeking campaign support for Warren Atherton.
  - 17. Athens George Cukor to BA, 1949 November 1; APCS 1p. (2)
    Willie, new picture.
  - 18. Leland W. Cutler to BA, 1957 February 25; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Alanson's gift to Stanford of “the Somerset Maugham manuscript”.
  - 19. San Francisco Fleishhacker family to BA, [1957 April 17]; Ptd card with autograph note + envelope 2pp. (2)
    Thanks for expressions of sympathy.
  - 20. London AS Frere to BA, 1954 December 30; TLS 2pp. (3)
    WSM suggested that the Freres contact Alanson in San Francisco.
  - 21. np [Mrs. Pierre Desautels] to BA, 1956 February 7; ALS 1p. (1)
    Travels in Europe, mutual friends.
  - 22. Paris Mrs. Desautels to BA, 1956 September 10; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Thank you for dinner, Pierre's travels, death of Arthur Wilson.
  - 23. Paris Pierre Desautels to BA, 1956 February 27; TLS 1p. (1)
    Coffee [for Maugham], BA missed anniversary.
  - 24. Paris PD to BA, 1956 May 4; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Thanks for congratulations.
  - 25. Paris PD to BA, 1957 October 1; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    To move officially to New York.
  - 26. np Marie Gardenhue to [BA], nd; Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 27. Mexico City MG to BA, 1956 August 10; APCS 1p. (1)
    Mexico.
  - 28. NY Consuelo Guy to BA, 1956 February 28; Note in Spanish. ANS 2pp. (2) + envelope
  - 29. Madrid Gabriel Garcia-Loygorri to BA, 1954 September 21; TLS 1p. (1)
    Maugham's itinerary in Spain.
  - 30. NY Gertrude Gardner to BA, 1928 December 31; ALS 3pp. (3)
    New Years greetings, family and social news.
- Incoming Haas-Swank (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1. Los Angeles Alexander F. Haas to BA, 1956 March 14; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    [Arthur] Rubinstein.
  - 2. NY Martin J. Heller to BA, 1953 September 1; ALS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Natomas, Paris.
  - 3. [San Francisco] E. Johnson to BA, [1957 October]; ANS 1p. (1)
    A magazine article.
  - 4. Yonkers Alva Johnston to BA, 1948 December 31; TLS 2pp. (2)
    Guatamala in the late nineteenth century, Wilson Minzer.
  - 5. np Jean & Jacqueline de Lagarde, nd; Signed Christmas card. 1p. (1)
  - 6. NY Jean de Lagarde to BA, 1952 April 4; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Financial business, Henri Beaujard.
  - 7. NY Sinclair Lewis to the Alansons, 1927; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    “My great sorrow that our friend George Sterling is gone.”
  - 8. Hollywood Montagu Love to BA, 1931 November 7; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Looking for bookings, Maugham, American Play Company.
  - 9. Washington, D.C. Salvador de Madariaga to BA, 1931 Julv 6; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    In Spanish.
  - 10. London Liza Maugham to BA, 1950 April 10; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Wants dividends sent to London bank, Maugham's birthday.
  - 11. London Lord Maugham to BA, 1947 March 29; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Thanks for food parcel, England's postwar difficulties, pleasure at meeting the Alansons.
  - 12. London Lord Maugham to BA, 1949 December 1; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
  - 13. White House, Washington, D.C. Kevin McCann to BA, 1955 October 10; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    San Francisco, evening with the Alansons and the Blacks.
  - 14. SF J. (Jack) Mitcheson to BA, 1951 May 3; TLS 1p. (1)
    Party at Stock Exchange Club during visit of Sir Leslie Rowan.
  - 15. SF J. Mitcheson to BA, 1951 April 14; TLS 1p. (1)
    Sir Leslie Rowan, preparations for luncheon.
  - 16. SF T.S. Peterson to BA, 1956 February 8; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Gen. [Wilson's] letter re: Ike.
  - 17. Stanford Norman Philbrick to BA, 1957 February 6; TLS 1p. (1)
    Invitation to attend a Stanford production of The Circle.
  - 18. SF Irving S. Reichert to BA, 1956 October 29; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Burial of Mabel Alanson.
  - 19. NY Leon H. Rosenthal to BA, 1930; ALS 3pp. (2) on Mrs. Rosenthal's letterhead.
    Congratulations on Presidency of the Stock Exchange, Anton Schutz, The Gentleman in the Parlor.
  - 20. Memphis, Tenn. Arthur Rubenstein to BA, 1956 March 21; ALS 1p. (1) + envelope
    In Spanish. Arranging a meeting in San Francisco.
  - 21. Beverly Hills Nela Rubenstein to BA, 1956 April 20; ANS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Thanks for lace gloves.
  - 22. np Alanson entry in Who's Who in the West, nd; 2 printed pages (1) with entry pasted on.
  - 23. Wheeler Sammons, Jr., [1957]; TLS 2pp.
    Who's Who in the West
  - 24. Washington, D.C. Robert C. Smith to Ronald E. Mahler with copy to BA., 1942 September 11; TL (carbon) 1p. (1) + envelope
    Diego Rivera mural in Stock Exchange Lunch Club.
  - 25. (see #24) Robert C. Smith to BA, 1942 September 11; TLS 1p. (1)
    Photograph of Rivera mural, Dr. Genthe's photographs.
  - 26. Teheran [Karen?] & Axel Speron-Fiedler to BA, [1956 December]; ANS 1p. (1) on photocard + envelope
  - 27. SF G.B. Stern to BA, nd; ALS 2pp. (1)
    Introducing Miss G.B. Stern (a very tongue-in-cheek piece).
  - 28. London G.B. Stern to BA, [1934] December 9; ALS 6pp. (6) + envelope
    Introducing Edward Mayne of Shell Oil Mexico, Willie's new use of exaggeration, Stern's book of short stories.
  - 29. Stanford R.C. Swank to BA, 1956 March 5; TLS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Alanson's plans to bequeath his Maugham collection to Stanford “it is by such gifts as this that a great scholarly library is created”...
- Misc. Incoming. First Names Only. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1. np “Arnold”, 1940 August 7; TLS 2pp. (2) with holograph postscript.
    Sale of Courbet painting, paintings of Antoine Wertz, Thomas Watson, patron of the arts.
  - 2. Cannes “Dick” to BA, 1956 January 1; ALS 1p. (1) + envelope
    Leonard Heller, lunch with ____ Alan, Willie out, weather.
  - 3. Pontresina “Dick” to BA, [1950]; APCS 1p. (1)
    Thanks for letter, aging.
  - 4. San Francisco “Cobbie” to BA, 1952 May 13; TLS 1p. (1)
    Health, “Cardiac Club”, Valley of the Moon.
  - 5. Tucson [Lionel] to BA, [1952]; ALS 3pp. (2) + envelope
    Arizona Inn & staff, food, Pontiac car, store in Tucson.
  - 6. Monte Carlo “Adrian” [Zleder?] to BA, 1956 March 2; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Desautels returned from India, show on the Riviera, visitors.
  - 7. London “Honor” to BA, 1956 March 11; ALS 4pp. (4) + envelope
    Coming to San Francisco, to do a portrait, Willte better.
  - 8. np “Margaret and Jill” to BA Easter card signed in Spanish., [1956 April]
  - 9. np [?] to BA, 1956 March 30; Envelope only 1p. (1)
  - 10. San Francisco “Ruth” to BA, [1957] April 10; ANS 3pp. (2) + envelope
    Thanks for gift, meeting with Rubenstein, Nick joins in greetings.
  - 11. np “Marie and Arthur” to BA, Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 12. np “Lousie” to BA, nd; Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 13. np “Lemuel & Carrie” to BA, nd; Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 14. np “Frances and Frank, Ann and Lionel” to BA, Signed birthday card 3pp. (2)
  - 15. Paris “Bill and [Thel]” to BA & Mabel, ALS 2pp. (2)
    Thanks for gift.
- Miscellaneous Incoming--Initials only. Letters to Others than Alanson. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1. inc d--no year given September 28 San Francisco [Favilua Tulhaud?] to BA, ANS 2pp. (1) + envelope
    “Thanks for your book.”
  - 2. np [S. Cardet?] to “Mabel”, 1939 January 31; ALS 2pp. (2) + envelope
    Sending “Unforgotten Years” and “Trivia”, Maugham might be interested.
  - 3. Monte Carlo [V.E. or V.G.?] to BA, 1950 January 26; TLS 1p. + envelope
    Guest list.
  - 4. Portsmouth, 1957 June 22; Typed envelope only 1p. (1)
  - 5. [New York] [Bertram?] to WSM, [1954]; ANS 1p. (1)
    Congratulations on Oxford degree.
  - 6. Monte Carlo [Adrian] Zleder to Mr. Desautels, 1956 February 9
    Thanks to him and BA for coffee.
  - 7. Zermatt [RVS] to BA, [1957 August 26]; APCS 1p. (1)
    Princess of Montenegro re: Alansons.
  - 8. np John W. Stanton to WSM, New York, 1942 June 10; TL 1p. (1)
    Copy of agreement with Alanson, legal-financial matters.
  - 9. Feldberg [?] to BA, nd; APCS 1p. (1)
    Christmas/New Year greetings.
  - 10. Canterbury R. [Tritton] to BA, nd; APCS 1p. (1)
    “Willie and Alan with us.”
  - 11. New York [?] to BA, 1957 April 6; Typed envelope only.
  - 12. France Unknown to BA, 1926 July 11; Partial envelope only.
  - 13. London [JTM] to WSM, np, 1942 [October 4]
    Thanks for food parcel, Robin now a Capt. and on staff of Gen. Spears, his bravery.
  - 14. Austria Unknown to BA, [1957 June 11]; Envelope only 1p. (1)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1. Arthur Wilson's death.
  - 2. Pierre Desautels promoted.
  - 3. Oroville Mercury Estate of A.R. Wilson, obituary for A.R. Wilson., 1956 August 11
  - 4. France-Amerique Douglas Black officer of the Legion of Honor., 1956 February 26
  - 5. France-Amerique M. Joseph Klein., 1956 February 26
- Clippings and Notices re Alanson (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1. San Francisco Examiner and News Call Bulletin Clint Mosher article on Maugham and Alanson's gift to Stanford of his Maugham collection., 1965 December 15
  - 2. Maugham signature., Photo negative.
  - 3. Oxford Cherwell, 1958 February 8; News photo
    Maugham at Oxford.
  - 4. San Francisco News, 1930 March 28; clipping
    re Alanson.
  - 5. Fresno Republican, 1930 March 29; clipping
  - 6. np cartoon of Alanson., nd
  - 7. np Obituary of Lord Maugham., nd
  - 8. Anaheim Bulletin, 1949 January 28; Photo
    Maugham and Alanson at San Francisco Stock Exchange Club for WSM's 75th birthday.
  - 9. Oxford, 1952 June 25; Ptd program 4pp. (4)
    the ceremony awarding honorary degrees Encaenia (Maugham received the Doctor of Letters).
  - 10. [Oxford], 1952 June 25; 5pp. (5)
    English abstracts of Encaenia addresses including WSM's presentation.
  - 11. np Bertram Alanson, “Alanson sets up memorial fund.”, clipping and photograph
  - 12. np Who's Who, “ Bertram Alanson”, nd; clipping
  - 13. San Francisco Chronicle, 1948 August 27; Article
    Alanson's 40-year anniversary as a member of the San Francisco Stock Exchange.
  - 14. Rio de Janeiro Vanguarda, 1928 November 12; Article
    Alanson's trip with other members of California's Association of Chambers of Commerce to Rio. (w/1 dup)
  - 15. San Francisco News, nd; (with 2 duplicates)
    “S. F. exchange head overcomes obstacles”
  - 16. San Francisco News “ Stock exchange honors veteran member, B.E. Alanson feted for 40 years mart membership”, 1948 August 27
  - 17. [San Francisco Chronicle] Herb Caen Article on arrival of Sir Gerald Kelly's portrait of WSM for Alansons., 1953 June 26
  - 18. np Article on Mrs. B.E. Alanson's death., nd
  - 19. [California and Oregon], 1930 March 27; 16 clippings
    Alanson heading San Francisco Stock Exchange.
  - 20. np, nd; clipping
    “Off to America” re WMS's attitude to French and the play Rain.
  - 21. np, 1940 December 24; Article (with picture of Alansons)
    Alanson's trip to Guatamala.
  - 22. np, nd; News picture and caption
    San Francisco Chamber of Commerce's trip to Latin America.
  - 23. Buenos Aires La Nacion, [1928 November 31]; Clipping
    Alanson's trip to Latin America with the California Association of Chambers of Commerce.
  - 24. Valparaiso, Chile (as above), 1928 October 23
  - 25. np (as above), nd; clipping
  - 26. Guatemala El liberal progresista, 1940 December 28; (2)
    “Guatamala is the true earthly paradise, Mr. Bertram Alanson tells us.”
  - 27. np Beaux Arts Ball in New York., nd; Clipping
  - 28. np Original cartoon drawing by S. P. Kahn Alanson.
  - Allan [UNK] “Norman,” 26 [UNK] 51 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Clippings and notices re Maugham I (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1. San Francisco News, 1949 January 26
    WSM's visit for 75th birthday to Alanson's house in SF. Picture inc. WSM, Alanson, George Cukor, Mrs. & Mrs. C.R. St. Aubyn & Frederick Koster.
  - 2. Heidelberg Life, 1957 June
    WSM at 83 revisits school where he spent 3 semesters in 1890's (described in Of Human Bondage).
  - 3. New York Herald Tribune, [1954]; Clipping
    WSM's 80th birthday.
  - 4. San Francisco Call Bulletin, 1941 February 3; News picture
    WSM & Mrs. Alanson.
  - 5. Chicago Tribune, 1949 January 16
    WSM in Chicago for publisher's party for Notebooks. Also information on Quartet.
  - 6. Oakland Tribune, 1949 January 26; (and 3 duplicates).
    WSM's 75th birthday with Alansons picture.
  - 7. San Francisco WSM's 75th birthday., [1949 January 14]; Clipping
  - 8. np WSM's introduction to Quartet, a movie produced by J. Arthur Rank made up of 4 short stories by WSM., [1949]; Clipping
  - 9. [San Francisco Call] Alanson's visit to Cap Ferrat., [1946 December 20]
  - 10. [San Francisco News], 1949 December 12; Article
    A Writer's Notebook.
  - 11. Chicago Tribune, 1949 January 15; Clipping
    WSM's 75th birthday.
  - 12. Sacramento Bee, 1949 January 28; News picture
  - 13. New York Herald Tribune, 1946 April 21; Clipping
    The movie The Razor's Edge, WSM's first screen play.
  - 14. New York Times Magazine, 1947 June 1; News picture
    WSM receiving degree from Toulouse University.
  - 15. New York Herald Tribune Books, 1942 May 3
    4 news photos of WSM in South Carolina, his retreat during WWII.
  - 16. Washington Star WSM's speech on the function of a novelist in modern society., 1946 April 28
  - 17. New York Times WSM's 80th birthday., [1954 January 26]
  - 18. [New York Times] WSM on WWII and plans for novels he will write while in U.S., [1940 October 10]
  - 19. Oakland Tribune WSM's reminiscences at 75th birthday, 1949 January 30; photo.
  - 20. np A Writer's Notebook., nd
  - 21. np Trio, a movie suceeding the previous year's Quartet., nd
  - 22. [San Francisco Examiner] List of people at WSM's 76th birthday party., [1950 March 15]
  - 23. Boston Interview following WSM's donation of Of Human Bondage ms to Library of Congress., 1946
  - 24. np Presentation of Of Human Bondage to Library of Congress.
  - 25. New York Times WSM's 75th birthday., 1949 January 26
  - 26. Boston Herald WSM with Doubleday editors and 1 vol of the original ms of Of Human Bondage., [1946] May 5; News photo
  - 27. Oakland Tribune WSM with unidentified friends., 1941 February 2; Newsphoto
  - 28. [New York Times] Book Review interview of WSM bv Robert Van Gelder, 1946 April 21; (1 duplicate).
    (with photo portrait and photo of ms leaf) Discusses early writings.
  - 29. np The Stars and Stripes WSM at 80, the Garrick testimonial dinner, daily schedule, Bertrand Russell and obscenity, writing and finances.
  - 30. State of Washington, 1949 January 28; 4 news clippings
    75th birthday.
  - 31. London The Listener, 1954 January 28
    Broadcast talk given by WSM on 80th birthday.
  - 32. San Francisco (4 different papers), 1939 January 19-23; 7 articles (7)
    WSM's coming visit to San Francisco.
  - 33. Manchester Guardian, [1954 January 24]
  - 34. np, [1939]
    The Lord Chancellor's breakfast.
  - 35. San Francisco Chronicle, 1950 May 26; (1 duplicate)
    WSM “richest writer in the world”.
  - 36. New York Times, 1950 October 19
    “Maugham starts television series” host in Teller of Tales, based on his short stories.
  - 37. New York Times, 1954 January 26
    WSM on Cakes & Ale, Presentation to Princeton of original holograph ms of novel Theatre.
  - 1. New York Sutton Theatre Program, 1950 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    American premier of Maugham's Trio.
  - 2. Paris Le Theatre du Symnaise. Ticket, schedule and program for Adorable Julia by Marc-Gilbert Sauvajon from the work by, 1956 September 19-25
    Somerset Maugham and Guy Bolton. Directed by Jean Wall.
  - 3. London Strand Theater program, 1957 June 16
    The Last Hero by Robin Maugham Repertory Players.
  - 4. London St. Martin's Theatre advertising card
    Odd Man In, a play by Claude Magnier adapted from the French by Robin Maugham.
  - 5. np, nd; TS 1/2p.